DANIEL DE SALVO BARIZZA

Email: daniel_barizza@hotmail.com
Linkedin: linkedin.com/in/danielbarizza

Location: Brazil

Professional Summary

Professional with 14 years of experience in software development, with the last 6 years focused on the leadership of multiple agile teams and the management of high-complexity projects. I have a strong background in systems analysis and software quality, with certifications in test management. I have led teams in the development of new products, system integrations, and customizations, ensuring deliveries aligned with organizational goals and delivering high business value.

Skills: Azure DevOps, Jira, Dynamics CRM, Trello, Miro, Scrum, Waterfall, Risk Management, Project Management, Team Lead, Reports, ETL, SQL, Gherkin, BDD, Selenium, User story, Use case, Black box test, White box test, Smoke test, Regression test, SLDC, Postman, SoapUI.

Professional Experience

Project Manager – Informa Solutions (October 2018 – November 2024)

- Managed the evolution of 8 different products, both SaaS and on-premise, across various areas, including
 administrative and financial management, contracts, journalistic production, media players (audio and video),
 and more.
- Led the implementation of software quality processes, stabilizing the bug backlog and increasing product reliability.
- Structured the software release process, resulting in more efficient, predictable, and robust launches.
- Conducted meetings and feedbacks with stakeholders, ensuring alignment with objectives
- Delivered internal training on agile methodologies
- Manage software integration projects with customers and partners teams, defining integration models.
- Collaborated closely with executives to guide strategic decision-making.
- Responsible for establishing and monitoring department performance metrics, driving continuous process improvement, client satisfaction, and reliability
- Provided consultative support to partner companies, assisting in the improvement of agile development processes, promoting higher quality and efficiency in deliveries.
- Directed the team's growth, providing feedback and supporting the individual development.
- I have led projects to generate reinvestment in research with securing tax benefits under incentive laws, and through technology funding grants for AI products development.

QA Tech Lead – Informa Solutions (January 2015 – September 2018)

- Managed backlogs to ensure continuous delivery and prioritization of essential features.
- Coordinated the test team, analyzed reported bugs, and provided technical guidance to developers, optimizing allocations and reducing the time to deliver fixes.
- Collaborated with the Product Owner to gather requirements and define system functionalities, aligning client expectations with the capabilities of the development team.

- Worked on the documentation of software projects, using models such as user stories, use cases, and diagrams, ensuring clarity and alignment between the product team and the development team.
- Wrote user interface tests with Gherkin to develop automated tests.
- Created dashboards to monitor team and project indicators, allowing for quick performance analysis and helping to improve quality.
- Developed SQL scripts to optimize data access and facilitate testing and bug fixes, and worked on data migration projects using ETL.
- Executed tests for Soap and Rest API with tools like Postman, SoapUI and Swagger.

QA Engineer – Informa Solutions (October 2011 – December 2014)

- Led the quality process for the software development department, focusing on test planning, ensuring product reliability.
- Created test cases, executed tests, and wrote test reports to document results.
- Trained the technical support team on new products, increasing efficiency in customer service and value delivery to the market.
- Analyzed and optimized quality processes and testing methods to increase coverage of verifications.
- Prioritized and managed the software maintenance backlog.
- Wrote technical documentation, including user manuals, configuration guides, and release notes.

IT Support - Informa Solutions

(October 2010 - September 2011)

- Technical support to clients for software-related issues and questions.
- Installation and updates of software in client environments.
- Trained end-users for better utilization of the systems.
- Created FAQs for operational support, improving user autonomy.

Education

- Specialization in Strategic Business Management (UPM Presbyterian Mackenzie University)
- Technologist (Undergraduate Level) in Information Technology and Business (FATEC São José do Rio Preto College of Technology)

Certifications

- CTAL-TM Certified Tester Advanced Level Test Manager International Software Testing Qualifications Board (ISTQB)
- CTFL Certified Tester Foundation Level
 International Software Testing Qualifications Board (ISTQB)

Languages

- English B2 (Intermediate-Advanced) Experience in technical communication and global meetings;
- Portuguese Native.